ADITI SONAWANE

Bloomington, IN | aditi.sonawane2212@gmail.com | +1 (812)606-7352 | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly ambitious tech enthusiast with strong software engineering skills. Experienced in .NET development, SOL databases, and DevOps tools. Proficient in C#, Python, Java, ASP.NET MVC, and REST APIs. Committed to continuous learning and growth while solving real-time problems efficiently.

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Computer Science

Indiana University Bloomington, Bloomington, IN

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Engineering

Savitribai Phule Pune University, Pune, Maharashtra, India

GPA: 8.29/10

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: C#, Python, Java, Javascript, HTML/CSS

- Databases: SQL Server, MySQL
- Frameworks and Libraries: ASP. Net MVC, REST APIs
- DevOps and Tools: Jenkins CI/CD, Git, Rally, JIRA

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Intern, Bloom Insurance, Bloomington, IN

05/2023 - 12/2023

08/2022 - 05/2024

08/2016 - 05/2020

GPA: 3.9/4.0

- Specialized in developing and maintaining custom .NET application using the MVC architecture, along with technologies such as C#, AJAX, JavaScript, and HTML, to ensure their smooth functioning.
- Collaborating with SQL Developers to design and implement database objects in a .NET environment and conducting regular code reviews for high-quality, maintainable code.

Software Developer, Cognizant Technology Solutions, India

11/2020 - 06/2022

- Successfully developed and managed software to create and alter the insurance policy forms and leveraged the knowledge of Agile methodologies, ASP. Net, Entity Framework, SOL Server, Jenkins, GitHub, CI/CD Pipeline.
- Developed various functionalities on user interface to enhance the user experience.
- Designed user stories and instruction manuals for sprint planning.

PROJECTS

CI/CD Pipeline using AWS, Indiana University Bloomington

02/2023 - 05/2023

- Built 'CommunityConnect', a cloud-based communication platform for neighborhoods using AWS, enabling seamless communication between neighbors, incorporating features such as high-priority email notifications for important posts.
- Implemented an efficient CI/CD pipeline with AWS CodeBuild, CodeDeploy, CodePipeline, and EC2 for reliable, accelerated code deployment while optimizing costs.

Sentiment Analysis for Amazon Reviews, Indiana University Bloomington

02/2023 - 04/2023

- Led a team of four in developing a sentiment analysis application using Data Mining techniques and advanced Machine Learning models to accurately predict the sentiment (positive or negative) of Amazon reviews. Achieved a 98% of high test accuracy with DistilBERT.
- Streamlined the deployment of the application on Streamlit, ensuring a seamless and user-friendly experience for end-users.

Social Network. Indiana University Bloomington

10/2022 - 12/2022

- Developed a social media website for book readers using Content Management System Sanity and ReactJS.
- Collaborated with a team of 3 to develop features of social media platforms like the Homepage, upload post, like, comment, save posts, search for users, posts, look for posts based on genre, etc.
- Successfully hosted the website using Netlify.

Data design of Google Play Store Apps for Market Insights, Indiana University Bloomington

11/2022 - 12/2022

Utilized Google Play Store Apps as the database and identified user groups. Addressed key questions on hiring developers, app success rates, and advertising-app alignment. Applied MySQL, Neo4j, and Python for comprehensive analysis, providing robust market insights and app suitability for promotions.

Online Bill Payment Portal Using ASP.NET MVC and Entity Framework, Personal

04/2021 - 04/2021

- Developed an application based on the MVC Architecture in ASP.Net along with Entity Framework Code-First Approach.
- Successfully implemented an option for vendors to register their service in the portal and view a list of customers who have selected their service and their payment status. Also provided a facility for customers to choose the payment option from multiple options such as UPI, Debit/Credit card, etc.

Bank Data Classification using Python-Django Framework, Pune University

08/2019 - 05/2020

- Collaborated with a team of 4 to develop a real-time Classification System for Customer Acquisition, Customer Retention and Loan Prediction using Data Analysis algorithms such as C4.5 and Random Forest.
- Trained the model on existing databases based on the attributes such as Customer Age, Education, Credit score, etc.
- Implemented authentication and security using Django and utilized Python, Django, HTML and CSS to build the system.